[MAN 06A panting]
[chuckles]
[THOMAS MICHAELSON groans]
You're mad!
[ENDERS]
There really is no difference
between you and a swine!
Even your pleas before death
sound like a squealing animal's!
[THOMAS MICHAELSON]
No! Don't!
- -[ENDERS grunts]
- -[THOMAS MICHAELSON screams]
What a fine evening
this has been.
There really is a
different zest to killing
using your own hands.
A gun can be so
clinical and unfeeling.
I'll have to implement it
into my hunting regime.
[knocking]
[WILLIAM]
Lord Enders?
[gasps]
[WILLIAM]
It's Moriarty. Forgive me.
[ENDERS]
Not Moriarty!
This is bad! What do I do?
If he finds the carcass,
I'm finished!
[WILLIAM]
I'm letting myself in.
[gasps]
[WILLIAM]
Lord Enders? Are you in here?
[ENDERS]
Wait. I'm just-- Just a moment!
Oh.
[ENDERS gasps]
[WILLIAM] Dear sir,
it seems a murder has occurred.
Surely, not by your hand?
[ENDERS]
No! This isn't how it looks!
I can explain!
Listen! He attacked me with
a knife just moments ago!
He's the criminal here!
Understand?
[WILLIAM]
Was the motivation burglary?
[ENDERS]
Yes! Exactly! He's a thief!
Who knows how long
this despicable vermin
was lurking in my stateroom!
[WILLIAM] He wasn't very
effective at his craft.
The room hasn't been ransacked
and nothing appears missing.
Moreover,
the knife was thrust through
his heart without hesitation.
Not only that.
From what I can tell,
the blade's handle
is exquisitely made.
It doesn't strike me
as the sort of weapon
a commoner would
carry with them.
[WILLIAM]
It must belong to you.
[gasps] Are you doubting
my word, Moriarty?
[WILLIAM]
No.
After all, you are a gentleman.
Why shouldn't I believe
what you've told me?
And on top of that,
why would someone in your
position commit such an act?
Murdering a commoner without
any reason? It's laughable.
Right! It's ludicrous!
To us, but the
circumstantial evidence
might not convince
an outside party,
such as law enforcement,
for example.
Has anyone other than myself
seen what transpired here?
No. Just you.
Well, that simplifies matters.
Might I suggest we simply
discard the body overboard?
Fortunately, we are at
sea on a moonless night.
You couldn't ask for a more
favourable set of circumstances.
We can toss this rotten apple
without anyone seeing.
[WILLIAM]
Are you ready?
Yes.
[BOTH]
Heave, ho!
[WILLIAM grunts]
Pardon me.
You're fine. No harm.
I suppose we should
be getting back.
There's nothing for you
to be concerned about.
No one noticed a thing.
Yes, but...
On the off chance someone
does realize he is missing,
the man was obviously
an alcoholic.
They'll assume he was inebriated
and fell over the side.
On ocean voyages, passengers
go missing all the time.
You've a point.
Yes! The blame
would fall on him!
It goes without saying,
but this entire affair is--
[WILLIAM grunts]
Of course. Our little secret.
I owe you for this, Moriarty!
My, I can barely
contain my excitement!
But the ballet performance
won't be until tonight.
Is it not a trifle early for you
to be positively beside
yourself with anticipation?
[NOBLEMAN 06A]
Not at all.
Lord Enders has
gone to the trouble of
saving a choice seat for me.
He really is a true nobleman.
My word. How generous of him.
They must be the
best in the house.
[inaudible]
[AUDIENCE clapping]
Bravissimo! Marvellous!
They'll talk of this
for years to come!
To think we saw it.
[NOBLEMAN 06A]
A triumphant showing.
And with the conclusion
of the first act,
I'll be taking my leave.
[ENDERS] So soon?
But the ballet hasn't ended yet.
Well, in truth, I actually
have a seat saved for me
on the front row
for the second act.
You can't be serious.
It's madness to sit
amongst all the commoners!
Yes, while I'll be
a tad uncomfortable
surrounded by the lower classes,
it's worth being
closer to the stage.
[ENDERS sighs]
Is that so?
Well then, at least
be mindful down there.
Between us, I had the
most unpleasant encounter
with their kind last night.
[NOBLEMAN 06A]
Totally inexcusable.
I'll take your advice to
heart and remain vigilant.
Thank you again.
[ENDERS] And to think
I respected the man.
[knocking]
[WILLIAM] Lord Enders,
might I have a moment with you?
[ENDERS laughs]
Moriarty!
Uh, what's wrong?
Your face is positively grim.
[WILLIAM] Actually,
the matter warrants the
expression.
I have to ask...
Regarding our burglar...
Are you absolutely sure
you killed the man?
[ENDERS]
What?!
[WILLIAM]
I hope I'm mistaken.
Just what are you saying?!
How could he be alive after we
threw the damn body overboard?
[WILLIAM] Yes. It sounds
like fantasy, but look...
[ENDERS gasps]
Down in the audience.
Towards the left.
Quite close to
the front of the stage.
[ENDERS] And what exactly
am I looking for?
[WILLIAM]
A bit more to the side.
On the fourth row.
Three seats from the end.
Do you see him now?
[ENDERS gasps]
But that's--!
The thief from
your room last evening...
...very much alive.
[ENDERS]
That's not possible!
I killed him
with my own two hands!
It's difficult for me
to believe, too.
And yet, I've no choice
but to trust my eyes.
I wanted to inform you
as soon as possible.
[ENDERS gasps] I see.
Very good of you, Moriarty.
Forgive me,
but I must take my leave!
Our lead dashes off.
Onto the second act.
[ENDERS panting]
[WOMAN 07A yelps]
[ENDERS]
This is bad! Really bad!
I killed him!
So what in hell's
name is going on?!
What if he survived
and somehow managed
to swim aboard the ship?
No! Get a grip!
I'm positive he was dead!
I've killed enough people;
I ought to know!
But I have to be sure!
[ENDERS grunts]
[ENDERS pants]
[ENDERS]
Where'd he go?! You!
What happened to the man
who was sitting there?!
Tell me which direction he went.
I'll pay you handsomely!
There's no need
to give me any money, sir.
He got up and left through
that doorway just now.
You're bloody welcome!
[ENDERS] Damn! Damn! Damn!
Then he is alive!
If he tells anyone
about what happened,
how I tried to kill him,
there'll be an investigation!
It could be ruinous for me!
[music plays]
[MORAN]
Director,
our lead should be hitting
his mark as scheduled.
- -[footsteps]
- -[ENDERS panting]
[ENDERS] This way.
I'm certain he came down here.
All that's left is to
find where he's hiding--
[ENDERS] You've put me
through a great deal of trouble.
[ENDERS gasps]
He is dead.
Then how did he...?
What's the meaning of this?!
I saw you walking
in the hallway!
You rotten scum!
You miserable--!
I knew it! I snuffed
him out last night!
So then how did he
come back to life
only to wind up dead
all over again?!
Wait.
How do I know he won't suddenly
resurrect a second time?
I won't make the same mistake.
I'll have to kill him once more.
And this time
be absolutely sure.
He's ready. It's set.
Waiting for your cue.
Go ahead and raise him up.
[MORAN]
Understood.
[ENDERS]
Die! Die! Die!
You persistent unwashed filth!
Never will you again
come back to life!
Stay dead this time!
You rotten no good!
[ENDERS grunting]
[gasps]
[screams] He just
killed that man!
No, he was already
dead, though.
And I was making sure...
[AUDIENCE 07A] He stabbed
the pour soul in cold blood!
[AUDIENCE 07B] I-It isn't part
of the show! This is real!
[AUDIENCE 07A]
What a monster!
[AUDIENCE 07B] He killed him
right there on the stage?
Wait. Unless I'm mistaken,
is that not Lord Blitz Enders?
[gasps]
[AUDIENCE murmuring]
[AUDIENCE 07C]
It can't be.
[AUDIENCE 07D]
But he's an aristocrat.
[AUDIENCE 07E]
How could he do such a thing?
Then the stories
about him are true.
He does hunt people,
and now he's doing it here!
[NOBLEWOMAN 07B]
How awful! He's a murderer!
[AUDIENCE 07F] What gives you
the right to take a human life?
[AUDIENCE shouting]
Human life, you say?
Come now. Don't make me laugh.
You think you've witnessed
the murder of a commoner?
Fools! I can do as
I please with these beasts!
[AUDIENCE gasps]
This is Noah's Ark,
vessel for the chosen!
If you're not of noble blood,
you're no better than livestock!
And I have every right to decide
whether you live or die
by my hands!
[NOBLEMAN 06A grunts]
He's gone completely mad!
No matter what you call it,
you've still committed murder!
[gasps] You hypocritical cad!
You've always look down
on the peasants,
the same as me,
and don't pretend otherwise!
Don't you dare
compare me to yourself!
I'm not some heartless killer!
[ENDERS grunts]
You traitor!
[AUDIENCE yells]
[ENDERS grunts]
[ENDERS groans]
[SHIPMAN 07A]
Stop him!
[SHIPMAN 07B]
Apprehend that man!
[SHIPMAN 07A]
Don't let him escape!
[SHIPMAN 07B]
Seize him!
[HOLMES]
Hmm.
Now that's interesting.
[ENDERS panting]
[ENDERS grunts]
[SHIPMAN 07C]
Stop there!
[SHIPMEN shout]
[panting]
[CROWD murmurs]
[NOBLEMAN 06A grunts]
He's up there, on the mast!
[ENDERS cackles]
[ENDERS] Those beasts!
They can't reach me up here!
For the rest of
their pointless lives,
they'll be beneath me,
looking up!
For I am the chosen among men,
a true successor of Noah!
[cackling]
[ENDERS yelps]
[gasping]
[gasps]
[yells]
[ENDERS]
Moriarty...
[WILLIAM chuckles]
[ENDERS gasps]
[ENDERS screams]
You're back. Would
you care for some tea?
[MORAN]
Nah. Make it a whisky.
[LOUIS] We have the
bottle ready for you.
So what was the
sentiment around town?
[MORAN]
Everyone's in an uproar.
Death on the Noahtic's
maiden voyage?
Naturally everyone's
talking about it.
The cat's out of the bag and
there's no hiding it.
It gets better. There's
a rumor going around
that Enders hunted people
on his estate grounds.
In response,
some MPs in the House of
Commons are speaking out,
demanding for a full
investigation of his properties.
When a search is
finally carried out
and the remains of
those who were hunted
by the late Lord Enders
are eventually unearthed,
I don't see how the country
could be anything but appalled.
Your smile tells me
you must have
already taken a few measures
into your own hands.
[WILLIAM] My brother's
exercising some influence.
It'll likely turn out
to be favorable.
No getting past--
that was a large-scale
operation we undertook.
Can't expect the clean-up
to be any different.
Right, Fred?
Hey, Fred.
Tch. Mister personality
over there.
But, really,
despite its complexity,
I'm surprised how
smoothly things went.
You must have had
the entire painting
visualized from the beginning.
Yes,
but it only went off without a
hitch because of those involved.
What's more,
one unresolved matter
causes me some trepidation.
[WILLIAM]
While it's still too early
to ascertain the
threat this man poses,
no doubt I'll be forced to make
some inquiries concerning him.
[MORAN] Give the word.
If this guy ends up being our
foe,
we need to know ahead of time
how to deal with him.
I saw him again.
He stopped me as we were
disembarking the ship.
And we had the most
interesting conversation.
[HOLMES]
Hey! Professor!
I've been looking for you.
I needed someone to talk through
that unforgettable
performance with.
Someone who could
keep pace with me.
That was quite the
spectacle, wasn't it?
But when it comes to ballet,
I think you'll find
there are far more
knowledgeable passengers--
You're playing dumb, professor.
I'm talking about the dramatic
murder in full view of everyone.
That was no ordinary murder.
Are you implying it
was somehow contrived?
[HOLMES]
We'll start with the body.
Our supporting character
died the night before.
From his jaw to the limbs
post-mortem rigidity
had already set in.
Meaning he'd been dead
ten to fifteen hours already.
Any way you slice it,
there's no possible way he met
his end up on that stage.
[WILLIAM] Your interests extend
to forensic pathology, do they?
Picked it up in France
where it's common knowledge.
This country is quite
behind the times.
But we're getting off track.
Back to the highly
irregular matter.
As the horrified
audience watched,
Lord Enders thrust a dagger over
and over into the victim's body.
Supposedly this was when the man
died.
Afterwards, the Count said
something very revealing.
Human life, you say?
Come now. Don't make me laugh.
You think you've witnessed
the murder of a commoner?
[HOLMES]
Meaning,
he thought he had murdered
his victim while on stage.
And yet the man had
clearly been dead
since the previous evening.
Odd, isn't it?
Indeed. Quite odd.
[HOLMES]
It follows, then that the Count
was under the
grave misapprehension
the corpse wasn't a corpse.
As if he had been
led into thinking
the man were still alive.
Stands to reason
someone was complicit in making
him believe this charade.
As in a third party?
[HOLMES] Indeed.
Despite how wild it sounds,
it's the only explanation
that makes sense.
My theory--
this ship served as
the stage for the event.
Through stratagems orchestrated
by persons unknown,
the Count became the actor
in a performance,
completely unaware of
the role he was playing
or its importance.
It sounds like
you're suggesting
some elaborate conspiracy
transpired on the voyage.
What was the end goal?
That is precisely the
mystery I'd like to unravel.
I'm merely stating if
such events took place,
this fiasco would make sense.
I did some digging
around the ship
to see if I could find
some additional clues.
But sadly, wasn't able to
uncover anything worth noting.
That is an awful lot
of trouble to go through.
Despite calling it
a mere theory,
you seem quite sure of yourself.
[HOLMES]
Of course, I am.
After you eliminate
every other possibility,
then whatever remains,
must be the truth
no matter how improbable.
It's odd. Seems like
you're enjoying this.
Why wouldn't I be? Despite
not having the foggiest notion
who did this or
their motivations,
the culprit has provided me
with an exquisite mystery!
You're a mathematician
after all.
You can understand my delight.
Like your equations,
the joy lies in the solution.
Yes. Guilty.
This has been
a stimulating conversation.
But if you'll pardon me,
I must be leaving.
[HOLMES]
Sure. Good day.
[WILLIAM]
How rude of me.
All this time, and I realized
I never asked you your name.
You can call me Holmes,
old sport.
Detective Sherlock Holmes.
[FRED] Next time
on Moriarty the Patriot  .
"A Study in 'S' Act One.'"